<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Bauhaus>
    <Home>
        <Name>Bauhaus</Name>
        <Founded>1919</Founded>
        <Founder>Walter Gropious</Founder>
        <Description>
            The Bauhaus, a German art and design school operating from 1919 to 1933 and founded by Walter Gropius, aimed to unify art, 
            craftsmanship, and industry. Key figures like Paul Klee, Wassily Kandinsky, László Moholy-Nagy, and Marcel Breuer 
            contributed significantly to various fields. The Bauhaus style emphasized functionality, simplicity, and mass production, 
            featuring geometric shapes and minimalistic forms. Despite political challenges, its principles influenced modernist architecture 
            and industrial desiogn globally, leaving a lasting impact on aesthetics and contemporary design practices.
        </Description>
    </Home>

    <Authors>
        <Person id="1">
            <Name>Walter Gropious</Name>
            <Picture>photos/walter.jpg</Picture>
            <Description>
                Founder of the Bauhaus school, Gropius was an architect and designer dedicated to integrating art, craft, and industry. 
                His functional and innovative ideas shaped modern architecture.
            </Description>
        </Person>
        <Person id="2">
            <Name>Paul Klee</Name>
            <Picture>photos/paul.jpg</Picture>
            <Description>
                A painter and professor at the Bauhaus, Klee is known for his unique style that combines expressionism, cubism, 
                and surrealism. His work significantly contributed to color theory and form.
            </Description>
        </Person>
        <Person id="3">
            <Name>Wassily Kandinsky</Name>
            <Picture>photos/wassily.jpg</Picture>
            <Description>
                A pioneering abstract artist and teacher at the Bauhaus, Kandinsky's work emphasized the spiritual and expressive 
                potential of abstract forms and colors, influencing modern art profoundly.
            </Description>
        </Person>
        <Person id="4">
            <Name>László Moholy-Nagy</Name>
            <Picture>photos/laszlo.jpg</Picture>
            <Description>
                An influential teacher at the Bauhaus, Moholy-Nagy was a painter and photographer who emphasized the integration of 
                technology and art. His experimental approach to media and design left a lasting impact on modern visual culture.
            </Description>
        </Person>
        <Person id="5">
            <Name>Marcel Breuer</Name>
            <Picture>photos/marcel.jpg</Picture>
            <Description>
                A renowned architect and furniture designer, Breuer is best known for his innovative use of tubular steel in furniture design, 
                including the iconic Wassily Chair. His work exemplifies the Bauhaus principles of functionalism and simplicity.
            </Description>
        </Person>
        <Person id="6">
            <Name>Ludwig Mies van der Rohe</Name>
            <Picture>photos/ludwig.jpg</Picture>
            <Description>
                A German-American architect known for his clean, minimalist designs that became synonymous with modernism. Mies van der 
                Rohe served as the director of the Bauhaus school from 1930 to 1933.
            </Description>
        </Person>
        
    </Authors>

    <Gallery>
        <Photos>
            <Photo id="1">photos/1.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="2">photos/2.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="3">photos/3.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="5">photos/5.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="6">photos/6.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="8">photos/8.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="4">photos/4.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="7">photos/7.jpg</Photo>
            <Photo id="9">photos/9.jpg</Photo>
        </Photos>
        <Author>Vito Vdović</Author>
    </Gallery>
</Bauhaus>